SUKANYA GHOSH

Master's Data Science, University of Koblenz

@ sukanyaghosh@uni-koblenz.de **** +49-15753690789 in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sukanyaghosh369/ nttps://github.com/sukanyaghosh1234



ABOUT ME

Talented engineer with extensive technical skills, business knowledge and a solid Experience of more than 4 years in India and Germany. I am currently working as a Data Engineer at BASF and would like to advance my career in the IT industry.

EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer BASF

Sep 2023 - Present

♀ Ludwigshafen, Germany

- Designed robust data models for efficient storage and retrieval
- Utilized Databricks to create and manage jobs and data pipelines, optimizing. Executed complex SQL queries to extract, transform, and load (ETL) data for various use cases.
- Developed PySpark scripts for data processing
- Constructed Power BI reports and Implemented CI and CD tasks within the DevOps pipeline.
- Extracted and transformed data from SAP tables using SQL queries to support various business operations and analytics
- Tech stack: Databricks, Power BI, Data Warehousing, SQL, Python

Software Developer

Axaat Concept

Mov 2022 - July 2023

- Planning and implementation of GUI in Angular.
- Tech stack: Angular, Typescript, DevOps,SQL

Software Developer

Sono Motors

May 2022 - Oct 2022

Munich, Germany

- Designing architecture and developed web app using Django.
- Tech stack: Python.Diango

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Marg 2019 - Oct 2021

- Pangalore, India
- Worked on IBM Maximo and developed Jython scripts.
- Initiated and facilitated a company-wide customer feedback program; analyzed feedback data and led a team to implement changes that resulted in a 20% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Tech stack: IBM Maximo, MySQL, Jython

LANGUAGES

English Bengali Hindi German



EDUCATION

MSc Web and Data Science University of Koblenz, Germany

Ctober 2021 - Present

BE in Computer Science MAKAUT, India

July 2015 - June 2019

STRENGTHS & SKILLS

PowerBI	Databricks MySQL
DevOps	Jira Data Modelling
Data Analysis Kafka	
Data Warehousing Microsoft Azure	
Python	Snowflake Pyspark
Numpy	Pandas Tableau
Product Management	

PROJECTS

AI-COVID

University of Koblenz, Germany

Mov 2022 - Mar 2023

• The simulation model aimed to provide vital insights for controlling spread of COVID-19. .

Prediction of Global Terrorist Attacks using Machine learning MAKAUT, India

m Jan 2019 - June 2019

• The model utilizes Exploratory Data Analysis to establish relationships between attributes.

Data Engineering Lab University of koblenz, Germany

- Worked on various tasks based on big data analysis using Hadoop and Spark frameworks.
- Tech stack: Hadoop, Spark, Java, python.